[{"id": "59029ed3cad1ec93f27df758", "question": "What is champagne substituted with to turn a \"Black Velvet\" cocktail into a \"Poor Man\u2019s Black Velvet\" cocktail?", "answer": "Cider", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b902", "question": "What color are many casinos decorated in to make patrons less aware of passing time?", "answer": "Red", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c627", "question": "In Astronomy, what does the \"Seven Sisters\" refer to?", "answer": "The Pleiades", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b5f", "question": "Who played Will on the TV show \"Will & Grace\"?", "answer": "Eric McCormack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393f5", "question": "What actor played the role of Jean-Baptiste Emanuel Zorg in the 1997 movie \"The Fifth Element\"?", "answer": "Gary Oldman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5cb70deaf96e155acab35d36", "question": "What two boxers fought in the famous match-up dubbed the \"Thrilla in Manila\"?", "answer": "Muhammad Ali and Joe Frazier", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bda6", "question": "What slot on the back of an arrow's shaft keeps it on the bowstring?", "answer": "The nock", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef653f6ce05a3942286e6a", "question": "What director founded the film production company named \"That's A Bad Hat Harry\"?", "answer": "Bryan Singer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c62b8540ae4aacefc17eee0", "question": "Who are the Pines twins in the TV show \"Gravity Falls\"?", "answer": "Dipper and Mabel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c695", "question": "The scientific unit named for Sir Isaac Newton measures what?", "answer": "Force", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015f61ffe83fe1f2a824c1b", "question": "In 1919, 21 people were killed in Boston due to a flood of what?", "answer": "Molasses", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0a5", "question": "What is the first name of Fidel Castro's brother, who became Cuba's acting president when Fidel fell ill?", "answer": "Raul", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338929", "question": "Which Wagner opera shares its name with a doomed ship?", "answer": "The Flying Dutchman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe768c8eec85e375820b2a7", "question": "The Ghirardelli Chocolate Company was founded in which city?", "answer": "San Francisco, California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c44f", "question": "What is the main constituent of an eggshell?", "answer": "Calcium carbonate", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c02d", "question": "To determine the percentage of alcohol in a bottle of liquor, what is divided by two?", "answer": "Proof", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe69fbb20565ad31a57c78f", "question": "What US founding father also founded the University of Pennsylvania?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a03b", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", which one of Peter's friends married Peter's maid, Joan, for a week?", "answer": "Quagmire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66c5da5bfecdd737e0893", "question": "What was the name of the world\u2019s last passenger pigeon?", "answer": "Martha", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59774295284458f1d7854421", "question": "What contestant-based reality television series aired in the United States originated in Holland?", "answer": "The Voice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c25f", "question": "What is a somnambulist?", "answer": "A sleepwalker", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c432", "question": "How many pairs of ribs are there in the average human skeleton?", "answer": "Twelve", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8de", "question": "What animals teeth were used as knife blades by Natives?", "answer": "Beaver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c86", "question": "Whose song \"Clubland\" begins his 1981 album \"Trust\"?", "answer": "Elvis Costello's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2f8", "question": "Which character did Raquel Welch play in the 1966 science fiction film \"Fantastic Voyage\"?", "answer": "Cora", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7359deec85e375820b24e", "question": "Who said, \"Courage is what it takes to stand up and speak, it\u2019s also what it takes to sit down and listen.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59774586284458f1d7854436", "question": "What ancient Greek god/goddess represented Necromancy?", "answer": "Hecate", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6aa3420565ad31a57c812", "question": "Who was President Gerald Ford's vice president?", "answer": "Nelson Rockefeller", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b97c", "question": "In the bible Zacharias and Elizabeth were the parents of whom?", "answer": "John The Baptist", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e0f", "question": "What 1993 film's title character has the first name Euphegenia?", "answer": "Mrs. Doubtfire's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65bfb1f3c0ead6880d60b", "question": "According to the Bible, where was Apollos from?", "answer": "Alexandria", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6000f1159a72b906b34e3d01", "question": "What name is given to a cockerel that has been castrated, and often fattened, to increase the quality of its meat?", "answer": "Capon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6014c4c3fbde8045e48466a1", "question": "What is the function of the skin patches (warts) on a warthog's face?", "answer": "Protection during fights -- Like many animals, male warthogs battle for dominance during mating season.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe51e681bf59ab7d2e380e1", "question": "Jambon is the French word for what food?", "answer": "Ham", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa5d", "question": "How was the country of Belize known prior to 1973?", "answer": "British Honduras", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397f9", "question": "Which UK band had a 1974 hit with \"Billy Don't Be A Hero\"?", "answer": "Paper Lace", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba60", "question": "Who spoke the first recorded message \u201cMary had a Little lamb\u201d?", "answer": "Thomas Edison", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921c", "question": "What city did the band U2 form in?", "answer": "Dublin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60078bd40eee65b76b9f266d", "question": "What was the name of the first English child born in the Americas?", "answer": "Virginia Dare (She was born August 18, 1587 in\u00a0Roanoke Colony.  She and about 120 settlers mysteriously disappeared.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdab9a20b8cce1e6fda7056", "question": "What is \"Coq au Vin\"?", "answer": "Chicken with wine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d69", "question": "Who published his last novel, \"A Passage to India\", in 1924, though he lived 46 more years?", "answer": "E. M. Forster", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c7e5877e98cb977789d8", "question": "Which Middle Eastern country's highest elevation point is Haji Ibrahim?", "answer": "Iraq", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339629", "question": "In what movie does Bruce Willis play a ghost?", "answer": "The Sixth Sense", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e6b698fb6c85e9e634ff49", "question": "What country's national flower is the Wattle?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a86", "question": "What poet coined the phrase \"candy is dandy, but liquor is quicker\"?", "answer": "Ogden Nash", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59e6b70ffb6c85e9e634ff4a", "question": "Who composed and played the score for the film 1953 film \"Genevieve\"?", "answer": "Larry Adler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6002436e4be4723ccac22196", "question": "In Jonathan Swift\u2019s \"Gulliver\u2019s Travels\", what is the name of the island inhabited by tiny people?", "answer": "Lilliput", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600cc0666de0eb824d4052d9", "question": "What is the most populous city in Australia?", "answer": "Sidney", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a33a", "question": "What actress played 4 roles in the 1975 film \"Trilogy of Terror\"?", "answer": "Karen Black", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba24", "question": "How many World Professional Snooker championships did Joe Davis win?", "answer": "15", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5d6", "question": "How many yards are there in a mile?", "answer": "1760", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b383", "question": "Who was America's first billionaire?", "answer": "John D. Rockefeller", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388a7", "question": "What George Orwell book foresees Oceania, Eurasia and Eastasia?", "answer": "1984", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefbe696ce05a3942286eef", "question": "Who recorded the song, \"I Heard a Rumour\"?", "answer": "Bananarama", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cc0", "question": "What mythical bird dies in flames and is reborn from the ashes?", "answer": "Phoenix", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febaad87e83c707845b20e2", "question": "Who created the centigrade scale, which was later renamed in his honor?", "answer": "Anders Celsius", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af2d", "question": "During which war did the Battle of Goose Green occur?", "answer": "Falklands War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c18c", "question": "Which UK Label is associated with a dog named Nipper?", "answer": "HMV", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c87b", "question": "What animal is sometimes also called the \"glutton\"?", "answer": "The wolverine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c492", "question": "The word \"laser\" stands for what?", "answer": "Light Amplification by Stimulated Emission of Radiation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e427fe83fe1f2a824bae", "question": "The Battle of Kursk is best described as what type of battle?", "answer": "A tank battle", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a67", "question": "Who wrote the children's book \"The Trumpet of the Swan\"?", "answer": "E.B. White", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e5f", "question": "According to the poem, how many spectators saw Mighty Casey strike out?", "answer": "Five thousand", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a375", "question": "What is the capital of Ukraine?", "answer": "Kiev", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5feddb156ce05a3942286d8e", "question": "Which well-known Hollywood actor claims he turned down an opportunity to be a member of the Backstreet Boys?", "answer": "Ryan Gosling", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395aa", "question": "Who played Elliot Ness in the 1987 movie \"The Untouchables\"?", "answer": "Kevin Costner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a683", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Treasure State\"?", "answer": "Montana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd27", "question": "In Europe, what are measured in \"Paris Points\"?", "answer": "Shoe sizes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f25", "question": "In the King James Bible, all but three books of the New Testament end with what word?", "answer": "Amen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae72", "question": "What berries did pregnant women of the Middle Ages avoid for fear their children would be born with birthmarks?", "answer": "Strawberries", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d9f", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Buchanan?", "answer": "F. Scott Fitzgerald", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd09", "question": "What was the original brand of cereal pitched by Tony the Tiger?", "answer": "Kellogg's Sugar Frosted Flakes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea3ad4ff048f679a45ab2f", "question": "What is the shape of DNA known as?", "answer": "Double Helix", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9e0", "question": "Where are you, if you landed at Lindberg Airport?", "answer": "San Diego", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b614", "question": "First marketed in 1952, Pream was a brand of instant what?", "answer": "Creamer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390a8", "question": "What do the initials stand for in J. D. Salinger's name?", "answer": "Jerome David", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338912", "question": "What flowers did van Gogh paint most regularly?", "answer": "Sunflowers", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada1", "question": "Harry Alonzo Longabaugh was better known as who?", "answer": "Sundance Kid", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fbf", "question": "Who wrote the short novel \"The Old Man and the Sea\"?", "answer": "Ernest Hemingway", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59db76db0ab2c8f322317fe8", "question": "In which ocean would you find the Republic of Seychelles?", "answer": "Indian Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59008e77cf842fa4c4ba96b2", "question": "What two parties fought in the \"Battle of Jutland\"?", "answer": "United Kingdom and Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ca3dbb44f0f6af5b06663e", "question": "What is the capital of Andorra?", "answer": "Andorra la Vella", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a2", "question": "Who is known as Eminem?", "answer": "Marshall Mathers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e66", "question": "When subjects of \"Who's Who\" pass away, what companion volume do they move to?", "answer": "Who Was Who", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339db4", "question": "Who plays the Internet personality known as the Angry Video Game Nerd?", "answer": "James Rolfe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbb3", "question": "Who was head coach of the Notre Dame college football team from 1918 to 1930?", "answer": "Knute Rockne", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a732", "question": "What river flows along the western border of Illinois?", "answer": "Mississippi River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133accb", "question": "What color suits are associated with Japanese Ninja?", "answer": "Black", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5bb357612627b8fe95581be3", "question": "What is the capital of the Australian state, Queensland?", "answer": "Brisbane", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60160066fe83fe1f2a824c53", "question": "Saint Valentine is the patron saint of which specific disease?", "answer": "Epilepsy -- Some legends state that he suffered from epilepsy, while others say he cured other people stricken with this ailment.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe769e3eec85e375820b2b3", "question": "An archipelago of 169 Pacific islands known as the \"Friendly Islands\", Tonga has what capital city?", "answer": "Nuk'alofa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59675fb62b59efe0e9417e9a", "question": "What Country music singer had a #1 single with \"You Look Like I Need A Drink\"?", "answer": "Justin Moore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b291", "question": "What Canadian territory came into existence on April 1, 1999?", "answer": "Nunavut", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9f9", "question": "In what state did former Illinois Governor Rod Blagojavich begin serving his 14 year sentence for corruption?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afce", "question": "Paul Revere became a hero after acting as a messenger during what war?", "answer": "American Revolution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecd6a5ec223966ae8f88d5", "question": "In \"The Godfather\" Clemenza says to leave the gun, and take the what?", "answer": "The cannoli", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a245", "question": "In the TV series \"Seinfeld\", who does Michael Richards play?", "answer": "Kramer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b86a", "question": "What is the Syrah grape called in Australia?", "answer": "Shiraz", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a85c", "question": "What is the World's largest landlocked country by land area?", "answer": "Kazakhstan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7fe", "question": "What are the two landlocked countries in South America?", "answer": "Bolivia and Paraguay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397af", "question": "What television show's theme was played at the commissioning of the first space shuttle?", "answer": "Star Trek's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad9e", "question": "On March 1, 1872, what became the first National Park in the US?", "answer": "Yellowstone", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339539", "question": "What fictional town is the TV show \"Dawson's Creek\" set in?", "answer": "Capeside", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ca3e2844f0f6af5b066646", "question": "In mathematics which prefix refers to 10 to the power of minus 12?", "answer": "Pico", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c84a", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find hepatocytes?", "answer": "The liver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b49c", "question": "Which country was selected as a host of the 1916 Olympic Games, but didn't actually host them?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5feddc306ce05a3942286d99", "question": "Which character in \"A Christmas Story\" is never given a name?", "answer": "Ralphie's dad", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a530", "question": "What city is located at the junction of the Allegheny River and Monongahela River?", "answer": "Pittsburgh", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b84", "question": "What cathedral was the fictional Quasimodo a bell ringer for?", "answer": "Notre Dame", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b044", "question": "How long did the American Revolutionary War last?", "answer": "8 years", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d8d", "question": "What original literary work was the movie \"Gettysburg\" based on?", "answer": "The Killer Angels", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58ec22b48dc25ca9e12ef62a", "question": "Which French singer and actor sings the theme song to Disney's film \"The Aristocats\"?", "answer": "Maurice Chevalier", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac7e", "question": "How many dogs survived the sinking of the Titanic?", "answer": "Three", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ec", "question": "Which actor played the role of Edward Scissorhands?", "answer": "Johnny Depp", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f507ff048f679a45aad0", "question": "Necrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Death and dead things", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffa416fc73aa70ea0b70b0f", "question": "Which Hawaiian island is entirely privately owned?", "answer": "Ni'ihau (The island was purched by wealthy Scottish plantation owners from King Kamehameha V in 1864 for $10,000 in gold.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ded043ea2747c8aff16d25", "question": "What fruit is a cross between a blackberry and a red raspberry?", "answer": "Tayberry", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b160", "question": "What title was Mother Teresa given by Pope John Paul II after her death?", "answer": "Blessed Teresa of Calcutta", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5902a06fcad1ec93f27df76c", "question": "Which Bohemian city gave us the Pilsner?", "answer": "Pilsen", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aba3", "question": "Which sea is located east of Sudan?", "answer": "Red Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd81b26d0de9af39e9d4675", "question": "What was the capital city of the Aztec Empire?", "answer": "Tenochtitlan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea7815ff048f679a45abd3", "question": "What is the tallest type of horse?", "answer": "Shire", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bc0", "question": "David Bowie is known for his distinct voice type?", "answer": "Baritone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392fe", "question": "After returning from death in the movie \"The Lord of the Rings\", Gandalf the Grey's name changes to what?", "answer": "Gandalf the White", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a42c", "question": "The Himalayas are located on which continent?", "answer": "Asia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ede", "question": "What river provided the water for which Handel wrote \"Water Music\"?", "answer": "The Thames", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c496", "question": "How many throwing events are there in a decathlon?", "answer": "Three", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6000ed369a72b906b34e3cea", "question": "Which scientist formulated the law of universal gravitation?", "answer": "Sir Isaac Newton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6008dcfef4f3bc4a292f861d", "question": "Whose \"Civil Disobedience\" essay inspired Dr. Martin Luther King King. Jr.?", "answer": "Henry David Thoreau (Thoreau wrote it after he was imprisoned for protesting slavery by refusing to pay his poll tax.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8fb7401dd7bf43be5e852", "question": "What is brandy?", "answer": "Distilled wine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133991a", "question": "What was Billy Joel\u2019s first Top 40 hit?", "answer": "Piano Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c343", "question": "What is the sound a camel makes called?", "answer": "Nuzzing", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bc4", "question": "In 2006, David Bowie was awarded a Grammy award for what?", "answer": "Lifetime Achievement", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b7ffa193a3a814d89068c59", "question": "Who secretly married Sara Lownds in November 1965?", "answer": "Bob Dylan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8d5", "question": "In what country would you find the mouths of the Yukon river?", "answer": "US", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8ac", "question": "Which nurse was nicknamed \"The Lady With The Lamp\"?", "answer": "Florence Nightingale", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f48", "question": "What naval hobbyist produced the landmark book \"All the World's Fighting Ships\" in 1898?", "answer": "Fred T. Jane", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cae2", "question": "A \"Tiercel\" is the traditional term for a male what?", "answer": "Falcon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389d3", "question": "Which character narrates all but four of the Sherlock Holmes stories?", "answer": "Dr. Watson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58bb3380e368446ca7bd6844", "question": "In \"The Wizard of Oz\", what was the lion looking for?", "answer": "Courage\u00a0", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e851fe83fe1f2a824bda", "question": "What were the four humours that the ancient Greeks believed made up the body and determined illness?", "answer": "Blood, phlegm, black bile, yellow bile", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a49", "question": "What was the real first name of the jazz performer Duke Ellington?", "answer": "Edward", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aba5", "question": "Which country is the third largest one in Africa?", "answer": "Sudan\u00a0", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5f7", "question": "What gender are whiptail lizards?", "answer": "Female", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398fb", "question": "What Madonna video won the 1998 MTV Video of the Year Award?", "answer": "Ray of Light", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe36b250ada16518afdc039", "question": "From which country did the troll doll originate?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b37d", "question": "What was the first product to have a barcode?", "answer": "Wrigley's gum", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe0e439fcbed638185eaa26", "question": "What is the most visited attraction in New York City?", "answer": "The Metropolitan Museum of Art", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae26", "question": "Who did Anne Hathaway marry in 1582?", "answer": "William Shakespeare", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe52bf01bf59ab7d2e38105", "question": "What does \"quid pro quo\" mean in English?", "answer": "Something for something", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5937ea5908d98002fdd633a1", "question": "What is the largest body of fresh water in the world by surface area?", "answer": "Lake Superior", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5937eeec08d98002fdd633db", "question": "What is 2000 in Roman Numerals?", "answer": "MM", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc06", "question": "A crusiverbalist is someone who is skilled at what?", "answer": "The creation or solving of crosswords", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefc40d6ce05a3942286f2b", "question": "Who first recorded the song \"Ain't That A Shame\"?", "answer": "Fats Domino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe1ec33145fb29466707385", "question": "What is the primary ingredient in a \"hoecake\"?", "answer": "Cornmeal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b1", "question": "Who played the female lead role in the 2007 movie \"Stardust\"?", "answer": "Claire Danes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339448", "question": "Who directed the 1941 movie \"The Lady Eve\"?", "answer": "Preston Sturges", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a956", "question": "Which European country replaced the Deutsche mark with the Euro?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339723", "question": "Bruce Springsteen was given what nickname?", "answer": "The Boss", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a47d20565ad31a57c7bd", "question": "Who was the first U.S. President born west of the Mississippi River?", "answer": "Herbert Hoover", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7ba", "question": "What country borders Egypt to the west?", "answer": "Libya", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394bc", "question": "What is the name of Jack's pet parrot on the TV show \"Will & Grace\"?", "answer": "Guspo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afdf", "question": "In the year 1900, what killed over 8,000 people in Galveston, Texas?", "answer": "Hurricane", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f9f4100af848b908361b86e", "question": "What is the opening line of Rick Astley's \"Never Gonna Give You Up\" song?", "answer": "We're no strangers to love", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396a0", "question": "Who played the role of the principal in the 2007 movie \"Charlie Bartlett\"?", "answer": "Robert Downey Jr.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca22", "question": "What is the shadow-casting pointer on a sundial called?", "answer": "Gnomon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c32e", "question": "Most people breathe through one nostril at a time - True or False?", "answer": "True, over 85% of people breather through only one nostril at a time", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fede2126ce05a3942286dcc", "question": "In 1996, Nintendo celebrated a milestone in the number of game cartridges sold with how many?", "answer": "One billion", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8e1", "question": "What does FIFA stand for?", "answer": "F\u00e9d\u00e9ration Internationale de Football Association", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388b1", "question": "In music, what does a legato mean?", "answer": "It indicates that music notes are played or sung smoothly", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133906b", "question": "Who is the Babylonian goddess of love and fertility?", "answer": "Ishtar", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8fc", "question": "According to Toucan Sam, what should you always follow to find Froot Loops?", "answer": "Your nose", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b978", "question": "What is the name of the cup used by Christ at the last supper?", "answer": "The Holy Grail", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600244e04be4723ccac221a9", "question": "What artist's portrait of George Washington is the basis for the US $1 bill?", "answer": "The portrait on the current U.S. one-dollar bill is an unfinished work by the artist\u00a0Gilbert Stuart. It was painted in 1796.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339577", "question": "What is Scrooge's first name?", "answer": "Ebenezer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ded166ea2747c8aff16d32", "question": "Mead is made primarily from what?", "answer": "Honey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a52f", "question": "Which US state is home to Newberry National Volcanic Monument?", "answer": "Oregon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015ea15fe83fe1f2a824bec", "question": "The first time someone bought something with bitcoins, 10,000 of them were exchanged for what?", "answer": "Two pizzas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339228", "question": "What is \"Shawshank\" in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "A prison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6000f10a9a72b906b34e3d00", "question": "How is sodium bicarbonate better known?", "answer": "Baking soda", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdab31d0b8cce1e6fda7042", "question": "What celebrity had their dog cloned, twice?", "answer": "Barbara Streisand", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394ba", "question": "What \"Twilight Zone\" writer also created \"The New People\" in 1969?", "answer": "Rod Serling", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d90", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is Shad Moss?", "answer": "Bow Wow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7e8", "question": "What is absent in \"negative\" blood types like O negative and AB negative?", "answer": "Rhesus antigens", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c71a", "question": "What planet's four largest moons are collectively known as the Galilean Moons?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ab1b1ec4fda37788a9a1db4", "question": "Which once-common disease was also known as the \"Great white plague\"?", "answer": "Tuberculosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dff", "question": "What is the Roman name of the Greek goddess Athena?", "answer": "Minerva", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6002444a4be4723ccac221a1", "question": "What is the only work of art Michelangelo ever signed?", "answer": "The\u00a0\"Piet\u00e0,\" a masterpiece depicting the body of Jesus on his mother's lap, is the only work of any sort that he ever signed.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a38a", "question": "In which state is the Grand Canyon located in?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fec8793ec223966ae8f8816", "question": "Which year did American legendary golfer, Tiger Woods win his first Masters Tournament?", "answer": "1997", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab80", "question": "What country borders Sierra Leone to the north?", "answer": "Guinea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c24a", "question": "How many liters are there in the Impertial gallon?", "answer": "4.5 liters", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff25bff31a458464a93c47c", "question": "What dish do the Japanese traditionally eat on New Year\u2019s Eve?", "answer": "Buckwheat noodles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a244", "question": "In what film does the HAL 9000 appear?", "answer": "2001: A Space Odyssey\u00a0", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b60b", "question": "Mile High Stadium in Denver was built in 1948 and was then known by what name?", "answer": "Bears Stadium", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a0f", "question": "What was the name of Paul and Jamie\u2019s dog on the TV show \"Mad About You\"?", "answer": "Murray", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59db77380ab2c8f322317fec", "question": "In which country was Dominion Day celebrated until 1982?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae71", "question": "What does the Latin word \"circa\" before a date mean?", "answer": "Approximately", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5bd05b4540191c55fd523fb1", "question": "Which person is most often associated with SpaceX and Tesla?", "answer": "Elon Musk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe768b2eec85e375820b2a5", "question": "What does the orange color on Ireland's flag represent?", "answer": "Protestants", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5bbd529500d154d7af00b8da", "question": "Jarvis Cocker was the frontman of which British band?", "answer": "Pulp", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c54f", "question": "What is the name given to the animals that live their lives both in water and on land?", "answer": "Amphibians", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5f6", "question": "What cut of steak got its name from the New York City coach stop where it was first served?", "answer": "Porterhouse", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d47006f8e329de4f87788c", "question": "Who is credited with inventing the saxophone?", "answer": "Adolphe Sax", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7e7", "question": "What company produced the first computer to run a Microsoft operating system?", "answer": "IBM", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e948fe83fe1f2a824be3", "question": "What was Eleanor Roosevelt\u2019s maiden name?", "answer": "Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b681", "question": "Which airline absorbed the carrier \"People Express\" in 1987?", "answer": "Continental", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339638", "question": "Which Disney's cartoon character's love interest is named Prince Eric?", "answer": "Ariel's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60121ac063c99d48cd169b07", "question": "Where was the world\u2019s first speeding ticket issued?", "answer": "England", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab972886faa38a764be527", "question": "Which car manufacturer was the first to include seat belts as a standard feature in their vehicles?", "answer": "Saab", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f67", "question": "What pastime is the subject of the Christian Slater movie \"Gleaming the Cube\"?", "answer": "Skateboarding", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2f2", "question": "What US state has been governed by Evan Mecham and Bruce Babbitt?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e66", "question": "Who provided the original voice for Garfield?", "answer": "Lorenzo Music", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600782aebd51d85e222ab659", "question": "Who claimed he could \"drive away the devil with a fart\"?", "answer": "Martin Luther", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b13f", "question": "How many months did it take the Mayflower to cross the Atlantic Ocean?", "answer": "2", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58b8cea894b094db915830a9", "question": "What year did Google first release the Chrome web browser?", "answer": "2008", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfa1", "question": "A \"pigskin\" is another name for what?", "answer": "A Football", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eae", "question": "Who won Pulitzers for his plays \"A Delicate Balance\", \"Seascape\", and \"Three Tall Women\"?", "answer": "Edward Albee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdab8370b8cce1e6fda7050", "question": "In the legal world, what does GATT stand for?", "answer": "General Agreement on Trade and Tariffs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ecc", "question": "What baseball player is Santiago's hero in \"The Old Man and the Sea\"?", "answer": "Joe DiMaggio", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397f1", "question": "What was compiled and published for the first time, in New York, in 1936?", "answer": "Pop music chart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c067", "question": "With which Major League team did Randy Johnson make his 1988 debut?", "answer": "The Montreal Expos", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e1", "question": "What is the name of the first book in the \"Bourne Trilogy\"?", "answer": "The Bourne Identity", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339522", "question": "What silent film has been called the granddaddy of all Dracula movies?", "answer": "Nosferatu", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe737deeec85e375820b25c", "question": "During World War I, the territory known as South West Africa was a colony of which country?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd668aba5bfecdd737e0871", "question": "What is the best-selling cookie brand in the world?", "answer": "Oreo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65592ae7e414034b5aeb4", "question": "What material was the first artificial Christmas tree made from?", "answer": "Goose feathers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a553", "question": "Which three US states have shorelines along Lake Superior?", "answer": "Michigan, Minnesota, Wisconsin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600cc8606de0eb824d4052fb", "question": "Where is the world's largest Roman aqueduct that is still in use?", "answer": "Spain -- The Segovia aqueduct, built in the first century A.D., carries water from the Fuente Fr\u00eda River to the city of Segovia.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601219dd63c99d48cd169afc", "question": "What is a haboob?", "answer": "A type of sand storm", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8f63301dd7bf43be5e830", "question": "What is the traditional gift for a 40th wedding anniversary?", "answer": "Ruby", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b04c", "question": "The Treaty of Versailles officially ended what major war?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a867", "question": "Montenegro's coastline lies on which sea?", "answer": "Adriatic Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a335", "question": "What song has the lyric \"I saw a werewolf with a Chinese menu in his hand\"?", "answer": "Werewolves of London", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b432", "question": "What year did the Mau Mau Uprising start?", "answer": "1952", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8b67801dd7bf43be5e7dd", "question": "What city drops a giant Peeps chick for the New Year every year?", "answer": "Bethlehem, Pennsylvania", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f566fa33a95c66dc4fe767", "question": "Who directed the 1941 film \"Citizen Kane\"?", "answer": "Orson Welles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d39", "question": "The co-creator of Superman, Joe Shuster, was born in which Canadian town?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a153", "question": "Who is Placebo's lead singer?", "answer": "Brian Molko", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "591c36ad815febcc896f9269", "question": "Who runs the \"Leftorium\"?", "answer": "Ned Flanders", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60121d2863c99d48cd169b1b", "question": "The \"Maman\" sculpture in Bilbao, Spain is a giant what?", "answer": "Spider - The huge arachnid is modeled after the artist Louise Bourgeois\u2019s mother. It was her representation of her weaver mother.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5937ece508d98002fdd633c2", "question": "The Ishihara Test is a color perception test used to detect deficiencies for which colors?", "answer": "Red and green", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfac", "question": "Kainolophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Novelty, or new", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397d9", "question": "How many Red Balloons did Nena have in the pop charts in 1984?", "answer": "99", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bf6", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"A Death in the Family\"?", "answer": "James Agee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eee", "question": "What happened to Barry Allen after lightning struck the chemicals in his lab?", "answer": "He turned into the Flash", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f16af2f7c52aae91cc07e3", "question": "What type of fish is used to make \"rollmops\"?", "answer": "Herring", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a25f1156682715b82711cdc", "question": "Bristol, Rockingham, Chelsea, and Minton are types of what?", "answer": "Pottery porcelain China", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef93a36ce05a3942286e90", "question": "Which pop musician was deported from Japan in the 1980's for possession of marijuana?", "answer": "Paul McCartney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f52", "question": "What photographer had a twenty-year relationship with late author Susan Sontag?", "answer": "Annie Leibovitz", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394dd", "question": "What kind of animals are \"Pinky and the Brain\"?", "answer": "Lab mice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca86", "question": "What culinary ingredient did Hippolyte M\u00e8ge-Mouri\u00e8s invent?", "answer": "Margarine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59637219967692ea851899bd", "question": "Ford produced the Model T in only what color after 1913?", "answer": "Black", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fc2f523cee580c7f8fd1e5a", "question": "What was the deadliest maritime disaster?", "answer": "MV Wilhelm Gustloff", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a25eea66682715b82711ccf", "question": "Which European republic was the first to reach Australia in 1606?", "answer": "The Dutch", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b9a", "question": "What actress replaced Shannen Doherty on the TV show \"Charmed\"?", "answer": "Rose McGowan", "category": "entertainment"}]